VIKRAM KANOJIYA

Permanent Mailing Address:

House No: C-1/40 A, Madhu Vihar, Dwarka Sector-3, Delhi, Pincode-110059 Mobile No: **9318378521**, **9899775652** E-mail: vikramkanojiya2@gmail.com



Career Objective:

To work with a reputed and performance oriented organization, where my skill-sets can be exposed to challenging opportunities in the field of Information Technology and administration , for ensuring smooth operations and professional growth.

Career Summary:

An experienced and professional Information Technology platform with 6 years experience handling various types of Online Selling Portals and IT devices, software's managing. I have worked with renowned organizations and successfully managed, ensuring that all vital information is effectively stored and managed, and relevant well handled. Core competencies include:

- Ability to handle work load of small to medium scale businesses
- Information technology systems and devices etc.
- Operate of Websites, Printer & Scanner machine

Office Administration skill:

Maintenance & Control of important data / records / software's, Day to day office maintenance including all issues of the organization , Preparation of Presentation required for Board Meeting, Day to day Reporting to Senior's, Managed Front Office, handle mail distribution, Assist to executive director, coordinate administrative tasks like HR, recruitment, admissions, Maintain the office equipment's and conduct the office orientation training program, Keeps record of office inventories, Perform other duties as assigned by supervisor or executive director.

Software skill:

Complete exposure in a computer working environment. Operating Systems: (Windows XP, 2003, 2007, 2008, Windows 10) Photoshop, MS OFFICE 03/07/13 (MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint)\

Technical Skill:

- A+, IBM Devices, Cisco Routers/Devices, Switches, HUB, Cables, VSAT technology etc.
- Proficient in managing the efficiency of the hardware components of the computers
- Technically competent to troubleshoot errors or upgrade the systems regularly
- Configuration of print devices (Network and local on desktop), desktop configuration network
- Installing and configuration all the peripherals, components and drivers
- Handling and maintenance of LAN switches, routers, firewall, printers etc
- System Formatting Upgrade Os, Software, Driver

Educational Qualification:

- BCA from Pacific Institute of Management & Engineering(2010)
- 12th passed from C.B.S.E(Delhi)

Technical Qualification:

- ADCHN Pro Diploma from Global Technology Engineering Collage (Jaipur)
- Microsoft Certified (Server 2003)
- Microsoft Certified System Engineer from Microsoft
- Microsoft Certified Professional from Microsoft
- Microsoft Certified System Admin from Microsoft
- Microsoft Certified Technical Specialist from Microsoft

Professional Experience:

- Legal & Commercial Officer: Handling court cases and hearing or Arrange require projects insurance policies & all official work etc. At Taurant Projects Ltd, Mayapuri Industrial Area, Phase-1, Delhi (Nov 2018-Present)
- BDM: E-Commerce Marketing (Like Amazon, Flipkart, Shopclues, Paytm, Snapdeal, Ebay etc.) At Eurotrust International, NSP, Delhi (Nov 2017-Oct 2018.)
- BDM: E-Commerce Marketing (Like Amazon, Flipkart, Shopclues, Paytm, Snapdeal, Ebay etc.) At Sony Playstation, Sarita Vihar, Delhi (March 2017-Nov 2017.)
- BDM: Website Marketing At Theadmissionportal.com, Noida, UP (Apr 2016 Feb 2017)
- IT Assistant At K.R. Mangalam World School, Vikas Puri, Pincode-110018, Delhi (Jan 2012 Mar 2016)

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Create top selling hot products and ensured filing of all listing as per online selling policies
- Assisted new staff in learning the Online selling portals
- Updated all records and rating on website (As Soon As Possible) basis
- Assisted managing and controlling various online listings
- Assisted in preparing directory listing for quick positive response
- Provided technical support and services effective for management

Strengths:

- Possessing self confidence, determination, and dedication towards work.
- Open to challenges for maximizing skills and abilities.
- Strongly believe in lifelong learning.
- Having open-ended approach to the innovative changes

Hobbies:

• Royal Enfield Old Standard Bullet Long Ride, Listening & Singing Music, Internet Browsing

Personal Profile:

Name Vikram Kanojiya

Father's Name Shivram Kanojiya

Date of Birth 20th Oct 1989

Sex Male

Nationality Indian

Marital Status Married

Languages known English, Hindi

Permanent Address C-1/40 A, Madhu Vihar, Dwarka Sectot-3, New Delhi-59

Contact No. **9899775652, 9318378521**

E-Mail vikramkanojiya2@gmail.com

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the statements made in the above Curriculum Vitae are correct to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Delhi (Vikram Kanojiya)